shakespearesglobe.com 2019-10-22

# Privacy Policy | Shakespeare's Globe

Last updated on September 2018.

We collect personal data from you when you use our websites and services…

…and we need your permission before we can continue to provide you with our services.

In order to give us permission to collect and use your personal data you must be at least 16 years old or have permission from your parent or legal guardian. If you do not understand this section, please do not continue before you have asked your parent or legal guardian for help.

__

## What data we collect and why.

We may collect and store a variety of data from you, depending on how you use our services.

For example, we collect and store the information you give us when you: buy a ticket for a performance, a public event (eg talks), exhibition admission or guided tour; book a workshop, course or training session; make a donation; buy a product at our online shop; use one of the Globe’s websites, such as [Teach Shakespeare](http://teach.shakespearesglobe.com/) or [Globe Player](https://globeplayer.tv/); subscribe to receive e-communications; and during meetings with members of staff.

The information that we collect may include your name, email and postal address, telephone number, your credit or debit card number, bank account information, and other personal data.

We also record the way you use our websites, apps, and social media channels, and we use this data to learn, for example, how many people visit our pages, and what they are trying to find. To find out more about how this works, please read our [Cookie policy](https://www.shakespearesglobe.com/policies/cookie-policy/) _._

We use your data to provide you with our services but also to promote, analyze and improve our services. For example, we use your data to send you booking information and help with any questions you may have, collect your payments, and to make your experience more enjoyable when you visit us in person or online. If you have opted-in to receive marketing messages from us, then we may use personal data such as your purchase history, location, as well as the preferences you selected when you created your account, to promote and tell you about related products and services that we think you might be interested in.

## Who else has access to your data.

In order to provide you with our services, we employ the services of other organisations who process your data on our behalf. We call these organisations ‘Service Providers’, and they help us with things like payments, website hosting and development, data analysis, customer service, email, etc.

We don’t allow our Service Providers to use your data for any purposes other than those described in this privacy notice, and we do not sell or rent information about you to other parties.

At times, we may ask you for permission to share some of your data, such as your name and email address, with our co-production partners, associate companies and visiting artists to help them in developing their audiences. We will ask you if you wish to opt-in for your data to be shared with them when you buy a ticket for one of their performances. If you have opted-in, then our partners may contact you until you opt-out. You will be able to unsubscribe from their communications directly by following the instructions provided in their messages.

Apart from our Service Providers, we may also use and share your data with other organisations as we believe necessary to comply with the law, to protect you, ourselves and others, to respond to requests from public and government authorities (which may include authorities outside your country of residence), or in the event of any reorganisation, sale, bankruptcy or other similar situations.

## Your rights over your data.

You have the right to be informed about how we use your data. We cover all of the important points in this privacy notice but if you have any questions, then don’t hesitate to email.

If you decide to give us permission to collect and use your data, then you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. However, because of how our systems work, this also means that we will no longer be able to offer you certain services such as online booking and shopping or access to our educational content or press materials.

You can also request a copy or summary of the information that we hold about you, or ask us to correct any personal information you think is inaccurate. Your first request for information will be fulfilled free of charge but we will charge £10 for further requests or enquiries which we deem to be unfounded or excessive.

The quickest way of requesting a summary of the data we hold about you is to complete a [Subject Access Request Form](https://cdn.shakespearesglobe.com/uploads/2019/03/3707_Access_Membership_scheme_form_final.pdf) _.  _Please complete the form and return via email or via post to the address listed on the form.

You may ask us to delete the personal data we hold on you. We will consider your request and not reasonably refuse it. If we agree to your request, we will remove any information that identifies you as an individual. In both cases we may retain anonymised data (for example, your booking history) for business purposes.

To make a request for any of the above, please email.

Please note: if you have an account on [Teach Shakespeare](http://teach.shakespearesglobe.com/), you can remove any data held on this site yourself.  Log in to edit your profile, where you will be able to cancel your account.

If you have opted-in to receive marketing-related communications (emails, post, SMS etc) then you have the right to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes at any time. We may still send you important administrative messages needed to provide you with our services or in the event of changes, cancellations or other urgent situations which may inconvenience you if we were not to do so.

If you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please [log in/register](https://basket.shakespearesglobe.com/account/login "Log in or Register with the Globe") and update your preferences, or click ‘Unsubscribe’ at the bottom of our emails.

Finally, if you are unhappy with how we are managing your personal data, or aren’t happy with our response, then you have the right to file a complaint with the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/).

## When we need to keep your data.

As a business, we also have a variety of obligations to keep the data that you provide us. These include ensuring that transactions are processed correctly, identifying fraud, and complying with any laws and rules that apply to us and to our service providers.

For example, even if you close your Shakespeare’s Globe ticket account, we may keep certain data (such as sales, membership and donation information) to meet our obligations but for no longer than required or permitted by law.

## Transferring your data to other countries.

Please note that your data may be stored and processed in any country in which our service providers operate, and we therefore may transfer your data to countries outside of your country of residence, which may have data protection rules that are different from those of your country. However, we will take measures to ensure that your data remains protected at all times to the standard imposed by the GDPR.

In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your personal data.

## Security.

We use reasonable and modern measures to protect your personal data within our organisation but, unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system is 100% secure. If you feel that the security of your account or interaction with us has been compromised, please contact us immediately.

## Recruitment

As part of any recruitment process, we collect personal data relating to job applicants.

_Data Processing Policy (Recruitment)_

## Contact us.

**Data and Privacy Policy Enquiries**

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a8ccc9dcc986d8e8dbc0c9c3cddbd8cdc9dacddbcfc4c7cacd86cbc7c5)

**General Enquiries**

Telephone: +44 (0)20 7902 1400  
Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#98f1f6fef7d8ebf0f9f3fdebe8fdf9eafdebfff4f7fafdb6fbf7f5)

**Address**

21 New Globe Walk  
Bankside  
London  
SE1 9DT

We endeavour to answer all data enquiries within 28 working days.

_The Shakespeare Globe Trust_  
_A Limited company registered in England and Wales No. 1152238_  
_And a registered charity No. 266916_  
_Shakespeare Globe Trading Limited registered in England and Wales No. 997433_
